swimming.org 2014-02-10

# The Amateur Swimming Association (“ASA”) / British Swimming (“BS”) Privacy Policy | The ASA

The ASA / BS (“ASA”, “BS”, “we”, “our”, “us”) take your privacy very seriously. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to see how we will treat the personal information that you provide to us either when using our Site or in the circumstances when we collect data from you. We will take reasonable care to keep your information secure and to prevent any unauthorised access or use of it.

We process all information in accordance with the applicable UK Data Protection Legislation. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time and the change will take effect once the revised Privacy Policy is available on our homepage. Please refer to this Policy each time you submit your personal information.

##  The information you provide

We may ask you to provide information to us or collect data from you on different occasions, including at a number of points on the site, such as when you:

(i)         E-mail enquiries, contributions or your views to us;

(ii)        Enter competitions;

(iii)       Register to receive information; or

(iv)       Purchase goods or services from us.

The information that you are asked to provide will vary depending on the reason for the collection. In some instances, for example, if you purchase good or services from us, the provision of certain information will be mandatory.

##  How the ASA / BS uses the information

We will use your personal information to:

 (i)       Respond to your enquiry;

(ii)       Administer the relevant competition;

(iii)      Fulfil any contract that we may enter into with you

(iv)      Research purposes

(v)       Send marketing information to you in accordance with the provision set out below; or

(vi)      For other reasonable purposes for which you have provided such information

If you become a customer of ours by purchasing goods or services from us we may send you further information by post or e-mail that is related to your purchase by post or e-mail or contact you by telephone. If you do not wish to receive this information or be contacted write to the Director of Operations at the address below.

We would like to send you marketing information, by post, email, or SMS. By providing your information you are agreeing to the ASA/BS contacting you in this manner to provide you with such marketing information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

In addition, we, our subsidiary companies and selected third parties (including our commercial partners) (as shown on the Site) would like to send you marketing information by post, e-mail, or SMS. We will only do this if you have indicated that you are happy to receive such information (either when you submit your details to us or at a later stage).

##  Sharing information

We will share your information with our affiliates and third party service providers if necessary or reasonably required for any of the purposes above. Such third party service providers are not entitled to use your information for their own purposes. We may also share your information with third parties for marketing purposes (in accordance with the above paragraph “How the ASA / BS uses the information”) if you have indicated that you are happy to receive such information. 

##  Protection of information

We are committed to protecting your privacy and we implement a variety of security measures in relation to our processing and transfer of personal data. However, the nature of the internet is such that the data may in some circumstances flow over networks without full security measures and could be accessible to unauthorised persons.

##  Cookies, Web Beacons, Spotlight Tags

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disc for record keeping purposes. Cookies can make the web more useful by storing information about your preferences on particular sites, thus enabling website owners to provide more useful features for their users. They contain no name or address information or any information that will enable anyone to contact you via telephone, e-mail or any other means. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you would prefer, you can set your browser to disable cookies or inform you when they are set.  Information on how to disable cookies can be obtained by referring to either your Operating Systems Manual or your Browser Guide, or by contacting your Internet Service Provider.  However, given that we may sometimes use cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of our website if you do disable them.

ASA/BS, and associated organisations web pages may contain electronic images, known as web beacons or spotlight tags. These enable the ASA/BS and associated organisations to count users who have visited certain pages on our website. Web beacons and spotlight tags are not used by us to access your personal information, they are simply a tool we use to analyse which web pages customers view, in an aggregated manner.

##  Links

Our site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practises of these sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statement on those sites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected on third parties sites.

##  Your right to access information

You have the right to access the information that the ASA / BS holds about you. In order to do this, please make a written application to the Regulatory Compliance Manager, at the following address:-

The Regulatory Compliance Manager  
The Legal Affairs Department  
3 Oakwood Drive  
SportPark  
Loughborough  
Leicestershire  
LE11 3QF

The ASA / BS may require you to provide verification of your identity and pay an administrative statutory fee (which is currently £10.00) to provide a copy of the information that it holds. Please note that in certain circumstances the ASA / BS may withhold access to your information where it has the right to do so under current Data Protection Legislation.

##  Updating your information

In the event that there is change to your personal information, for example, your contact details, please let us know as soon as possible, in writing, to the Membership Services Department in order that we can keep your information up to date and accurate.

##  Contact us

Amateur Swimming Association/British Swimming, SportPark, 3 Oakwood Drive, Loughborough, Leicestershire, LE11 3QF
